# 你看 紅燒肉它們
Look! Red Braised Pork and its friends,
# 大腸 豬大腸
Chit, the Chitterlings,
# 在這拱這個樹枝哦
they're snouting these branches,
# 拱那個地
snouting the ground.
# 幫我翻地 到時候我就把象草種一排過去
They’re helping me turn the soil. I can then plant a whole row of elephant grass here later.
# 剛剛好
Perfect!
# 上次那個抽水機壞啦 就是因為這個壞啦
Last time the water pump was not working. It’s because this one was broken.
# 你看 現在我們把它買了一個新的回來
Look! We’ve now bought a new one back.
# 這個肯定可以抽得上來啦
With this one, we can surely drain the ponds.
# 那裡有魚 還沒 還不知道有多少啦
There are...Well, I have no ideas how many fish there are.
# 去搞一下
Let’s go get them.
# 小羊
Goaty!
# 羊肉包
Lamb Bun!
# 叫你 你就拉尿
Hey! I'm calling you. You just piss.
# 那個紅燒肉 我一過來它就過來啦
That is Red Braised Pork. It comes to me immediately upon my call.
# 紅燒肉
Red Braised Pork!
# 它還
It can’t,
# 它還沒反應過來
it can’t respond immediately.
# 哇瑟 你又胖啦
Gosh! You're getting fatter again!
# 是啊 適合做紅燒
Yea, right! Excellent for red braised pork.
# 你要進來嗎
You wanna get in?
# 你看 豬大腸
Look! Chitterlings,
# 這個A 這個B
this is A, and this is B.
# 這個公的是A 母的是B
This male is A, and the female is B.
# 走啦 幹活啦
Let’s go! I gotta start working now.
# 你看 上次我們的抽水機還放在這裡
Look! The water pump last time is still here.
# 把這個裝上 直接打火
Let me put this on, and start the engine right away.
# 這是山泉水來的哦
This is spring water, you know.
# 山泉水滲到這裡面來的
The spring water seeps into the ponds.
# 你看 這一條蛇頭魚哦 看到沒有
Look! Here’s a snakehead fish. See?
# 看到你啦
I can see you already.
# 抓到啦
Got it!
# 你看
Look!
# 一條 一條鯰魚 看到沒有 它躲在這裡
A, a catfish. See? It’s hiding here.
# 用力
Keep going!
# 它縮回去啦
It hides back.
# 這裡還沒有抽乾哦
Here is still not yet completely drained.
# 還有的哦
There’s still water.
# 抽不到哦
No more?
# 抽不到啦 我把這個拉起來
No more. Then I pull it out.
# 終於沒有
Finally, I am...
# 白來 看這裡有沒有大貨
... not wasting my time. Let me see if there are any big things.
# 這麼深
It’s so deep.
# 全是樹葉
Only leaves
# 你看 全部把它抽乾啦
Look! They’re all completely drained now.
# 就搞了3條 2條鯰魚
Just three fish, two catfish and,
# 2魚蛇頭魚喲 好像 是不是
two snakehead fish, it seems. Am I right?
# 4條 好像
Four fish, it seems
# 哦 這有3條
Oh! Here are three.
# 2條蛇頭魚
Two snakehead fish,
# 一條鯰魚
and a catfish.
# 上次搞了一條鯰魚 一條蛇頭魚
Last time we caught a catfish and a snakehead fish.
# 6條
So six fish
# 這樣算下去虧本啊
I think it can be considered a loss.
# 我放了那麼多魚
I have put so many fish here.
# 都不見啦
But they’re all gone.
# 好啦 不管它啦
Alright! Forget it.
# 回家啦 清洗一下
Let’s go back, and wash everything.
# 再也不放魚到這裡啦
Never will I put any fish here anymore.
# 我拿這個行啦 我拿這個刀
I only need to take this one. I’ll take this knife as well.
# 你看 這兩條蛇頭魚
Look! These two snakehead fish
# 看到沒有
See?
# 還有一條鯰魚
Here’s also a catfish.
# 這魚很好吃的哦
This fish is really tasty.
# 誒 它們是不是
Ey? Were they,
# 那天被我攪拌了一下
stirred by me last time.?
# 身上都受了一點小傷
They all have some small wounds on their bodies.
# 別出來
Don’t try to run away.
# 先放在這裡養著先
Let me keep them here first.
# 前兩天兄弟說 我們沒抓到魚
A couple of days ago, my buddy said that I couldn’t catch any fish.
# 他怎麼知道我們沒抓到魚 你看
How did he know that I couldn’t catch any fish? Look!
# 特意 他提了
Because of that, he brought me,
# 提了兩 兩個 這個牛蛙過來
brought me two, two, well, bullfrogs here.
# 5個哦 不是2個
Oh, five, not two.
# 拿2隻來烤一下
Let’s grill two of them.
# 最近很少吃肉 吃點這個牛蛙
We seldom have meat recently. So let’s have some bullfrogs.
# 你看 這個好肥呀
Look! This one is really fat.
# 肚子都好白 鼓鼓的
Its belly is so white, and so round.
# 現在把它處理一下
Let me take care of them first.
# 這牛蛙要把它 把它摔死哦
To kill the bullfrogs, I need to strike them hard.
# 你看 搞點這個生薑
Look! Put some, some ginger here.
# 搞點
Put some,
# 生薑給你們去去你們的腥味
some ginger to get rid of your bloody smell.
# 再搞點全南大曲
And then put some “Quannan Daqu" (local liquor)
# 全南大曲
“Quannan Daqu”
# 哎 給你們喝點酒
Ay! I give your some liquor.
# 味道杠杠的
Magnifico!
# 再加點鹽
Then put some salt.
# 再加點醬油
And also some soy sauce
# 再抽點油
Then some oil
# 油要搞多一點
I need a bit more oil.
# 你看 好啦
Look! It’s alright now.
# 攪拌一下
Mix them well
# 你看 剛剛給它喝點酒 馬上就醉啦
Look! I’ve just given them some liquor, and they’re drunk immediately.
# 把這個牛蛙 拿上來
So I put these bullfrogs, onto this grill.
# 來 上烤架啦
C’mon! Onto the grill now!
# 這個 烤這個牛蛙沒那麼快的哦
Well, grilling these bullfrogs needs a bit more time.
# 我去看一上兄弟家的兔子
Let me have a look at the rabbits at my buddy’s place.
# 他家兔子養了好多
He has a lot of rabbits.
# 你看 這就是兔子廠啦
Look! This is his rabbit site.
# 你看 這個兔子
Look! These rabbits,
# 好漂亮哦
are so pretty.
# 你看
Look!
# 一個都差不多有5斤哦
It’s almost two and a half kilograms each.
# 太大啦
Too big
# 可以吃啦 這個兔子那麼大
These rabbits are so big. They can be eaten now.
# 這種 這種灰色的漂亮 這種灰色的
This, this kind of grey ones are really pretty, these grey ones.
# 公兔子哦 好大啊 它腳趾
This is a male rabit. It’s so big, its toes.
# 差不多于六斤啊 這個兔子
It’s almost three kilograms, this rabbit.
# 把它抱回去
Let me put it back.
# 哎喲 你太胖啦
Aya! You’re just too fat.
# 你看 這個 哇 這個好大個
Look! This is.. Wa! This is huge!
# 灰色的 嘿 過來 過來 過來
The grey one, hey! C’mere, c’mere, c’mere!
# 啊 過來 不怕
Ah! C’mere! Fear not!
# 看一下你胖不胖
Let me see if you’re fat.
# 好胖啊 這個
It’s so fat, this one.
# 一身都是肉哦
It’s covered with meat.
# 軟綿綿的 好多肉哇
It’s soft like cotton, so meaty.
# 嘿
Hey!
# 這麼大的腳板
What a big foot!
# 公的 這個
It’s male, this one.
# 黑 放回去
Hey! Let me put it back
# 你看 雪白雪白的這個毛哦 眼睛都是紅的
Look! Its coat is snowy white, and the eyes are red.
# 最少七八斤
It’s at least three or even four kilograms.
# 肉兔子
They’re meat rabbits.
# 去不去我家 很近的走路都可以過去
You wanna go home with me? It’s nearby. You can simply walk there.
# 它不肯
It doesn’t want.
# 等他養肥一點我在[SIC]來
Let me come again when they get fatter.
# 現在全是母兔子 他說
Now they’re all female, he said.
# 他說現在要繁殖的時候
He said that it’s now the breeding time.
# 不能吃 是啊 等他有商品兔的時候我就再過來
So they can’t be eaten now. Yup. I’ll wait and come again when they’re for sale.
# 很近的 就相差不到50米
It’s nearby, not even fifty metres away.
# 搞點這個醬料給它身上
Put some, some sauce here onto their bodies.
# 看上去烤得有點乾啦
Cuz they look a little bit dry.
# 嗯 好啦
Um! Alright!
# 這個爐子太大啦
This stove is too big.
# 不好烤
It’s hard to grill well.
# 我怕那個烤得不是很熟
I don't wanna have it only partially cooked at the end.
# 換一個小爐子來
Let’s change to a smaller stove.
# 換來
Let’s move,
# 換了一個地方烤
move to another place.
# 那個地方太 太高啦
The one there is too, too high.
# 刷點這個醬料
Let me brush some sauce here,
# 讓它的味道
so that its taste would change,
# 更美好
from good to wonderful.
# 跑出一隻來
One has escaped.
# 啊 現在可以
Ah! It’s alright now.
# 烤得差不多咯 可以吃咯 看到沒有
I think it’s done now. We can start. See?
# 很靚的哦
It's beautiful, you know.
# 大長腿
Big long legs
# 好啦 好啦 開吃
Alright, alright! Let’s start.
# 給它們鬆綁
Let me untie them.
# 用架子壓著它們
I pressed them here.
# 我是為了防止它們逃跑
Cuz I wanted to prevent them from escaping.
# 所以就壓著它們
So I pressed them here.
# 開蓋啦
Let me open it!
# 哎呀 哎呀 別啦著這個
Aya, aya! Don’t hold onto it!
# 手都斷啦 哦
The arm is broken, oh.
# 嗯 好好吃啊
Um! It tastes really good!
# 它們的樣子好 很漂亮吧
They look so, really pretty, aren’t they?
# 哎 沒辦法
Ay! Anyway!
# 先把它手拿上來
Let me take off its arm first.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 搞它大長腿來
Let me take its big long leg.
# 你看
Look!
# 大腿啊
It’s a leg!
# 嗯
Um!
# 好吃
Good!
# 如果再烤乾一點
It would taste even better,
# 那味道更好
if there’s a bit less moisture.
# 嗯 它們腳趾
Um! Their toes
# 你看 搞一個大腿來吃一下
Look! Take a leg and have a try!
# 等一下
Wait!
# 讓你先舔一下
You can lick it first.
# 舔一下就可以啦 那個腳趾 好好吃的
Just lick it! The toes, are really tasty!
# 大腿
The leg!
# 嗯 好香
Um! It smells really good!
# 小狗
Doggy!
# 你可真有福氣呀
You’re really privileged, you know.
# 這裡
Here!
# 好不好吃
Does it taste good!
# 要聽話啊
Be a good boy, got it?
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 我要回家做飯啦
I gotta go home and cook now.
# 不做飯的話
Otherwise,
# 晚上沒飯吃哦
I would have nothing for dinner tonight.